Calvin Macintosh

443-977-1121 | Philadelphia/PA/19146 | calvinmac633@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/calvin-macintosh | github.com/Calvinmac633 | calvinmacintosh.com

SUMMARY

Proficient full stack developer with a background in actuarial data analytics. Professional experience working in agile development environment and a passion for cryptocurrencies, decentralized technologies, and creating responsive and user-friendly web designs. Excited to combine my technical skills in web development with my background in data analytics to create thoughtful, customer-focused designs that drive company growth and innovation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development: AngularJS, Cypress, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, JavaScript ES5/ES6, Solidity, web3.js, ethers.js, Handlebars.js, JSON, JQuery, AJAX, HTML, CSS, DOM, Heroku, REST APIs, Bootstrap, Sequelize, Materialize, Postman

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, FireBase

Other Skills: Linux, Windows, Git/Github, Google Suite, Microsoft Suite

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Dosel Australia, PTY LT, Philadelphia, PA

July 2020 – present

Javascript Developer – responsible for migrating middleware for a global, interactive web-based system for radiation compliance and medical accreditation.

- Handling and processing client requests for feature implementations and site changes
- Migrating legacy API calls from PHP to Nodejs
- Creating and updating AngularJS components to display dynamic data
- Identify and communicate bugs in database functionality to back-end developers
- Create, run, and update unit tests written against Nodejs API calls
- Collaborate with project managers to implement front-end components for optimum user experience

Willis Towers Watson, Philadelphia, PA

June 2017 – July 2020

Actuarial Analyst – responsible for preparing actuarial valuations of pension plans for Fortune 500 companies and national organizations.

- Utilized Excel to analyze financial results and research data issues for clients and internal usage
- Applied SQL coding to manipulate and organize client data to ensure privacy measures are accounted to protect clients
- Identified and communicated technical/analytical issues to project team

Independence Capital Partners, Philadelphia, PA

January 2016 – December 2016

Tax Intern – prepared various tax returns for partner firms, responded to and resolved tax notices sent by the IRS

PROJECTS

ETH Send | github.com/Calvinmac633/ethSend

- A blockchain integrated application that sends Ether, and a personalized message, to anyone in the world with a web3 address.
- Responsible for implementing back-end Solidity logic and properly communicating through practical front-end components.
- **Technologies Used**: Solidity, JSX, ethers.js, Tailwind CSS.

Coin Tracker | github.com/Calvinmac633/coin-tracker | delightful-pothos-e3fa43.netlify.app/

- Mobile application that lists over 200 different cryptocurrencies with real-time price, market data, and charting updates.
- Responsible for implementing front end React components and leveraging various npm packages to help display data in a UI/UX friendly way.
- Utilize knowledge of crypto and web3 space to prioritize the display of most pertinent data.
- **Technologies Used**: React.js, Materialize-ui, axios, and chartjs.

Password Generator | github.com/Calvinmac633/password-generator | calvinmac633.github.io/password-generator/

- A front-end application that uses Materialize-UI to professionally display a password generator. User selects different specifications, and a new password is generated every time and can be copied with the click of a button.
- Responsible for programming logic and display of the application.
- **Technologies Used**: JavaScript, jQuery, Materialize-UI, HTML, CSS.

Weather App | github.com/Calvinmac633/weather-app | calvinmac633.github.io/weather-app/

- A front-end application that builds upon a public weather API provided by openweathermap.org. Search by city to get current weather along with a 5-day forecast.
- Responsible for obtaining access to public API and using front-end logic to display data based on conditional information.
- **Technologies Used**: JavaScript, RESTful APIs, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS.

EDUCATION

Penn University LPS Coding Bootcamp, Philadelphia, PA

May 2020

Certificate: Full Stack Web Development (MERN Stack)

La Salle University, Philadelphia, PA

June 2017

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (3.5 GPA)

Major: Finance; Minor: Economics and Philosophy

- Business Scholar's Co-op Program La Salle School of Business
- La Salle University Honors Program

HONORS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Eagle Scout and Scout of the Year 2011 Dulaney District (Maryland), Boy Scouts of America
- Black Belt, World Seido Karate Organization